{"id":"2017_9","name":"Romans2017_9","memoryVerse":"“Therefore, since we have been justified through faith, we have peace with God through our Lord Jesus Christ.” –  Romans 5:1","dayQuestions":{"one":{"title":"FIRST DAY: Read the notes and the references.","questions":[{"id":"2017_9_1","questionText":"1. What was meaningful to you in the lecture?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_9_2","questionText":"2. What help did you receive from the notes?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"two":{"title":"SECOND DAY: Read Romans 5:12-14.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"5:12-14"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_9_3","questionText":"3.  Read Genesis 2:15-3:24. Who was the “one man” in Romans 5:12? What warning did God give him, and what harm did his sin cause? (See also Romans 3:9-11, 23; 8:20-21; 1 Corinthians 15:22; Ephesians 2:1-3.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Genesis","verse":"2:15-3:24"},{"book":"Romans","verse":"5:12"},{"book":"Romans","verse":"3:9-11"},{"book":"Romans","verse":"3:23"},{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:20-21"},{"book":"1 Corinthians","verse":"15:22"},{"book":"Ephesians","verse":"2:1-3"}]},{"id":"2017_9_4","questionText":"4. What do most people you know believe about humanity – that all people are born good, born neutral or born  sinners? What do you believe and why?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"three":{"title":"THIRD DAY: Read Romans 5:14-19.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"5:14-19"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_9_5","questionText":"5. List ways Adam (“a pattern”) and Jesus Christ (“the one to come”) are the same and ways they differ. How did Jesus bring more good than all that Adam destroyed? ","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_9_6","questionText":"6. What is the “gift”? Why do verses 15-17 mention it so often, and what is your response to it?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_9_7","questionText":"7. What unites people to Adam, and what unites them to Christ? To whom are you united, and how do you know? (See also John 3:7-21; Romans 10:9-13; or other Bible passages.) ","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"John","verse":"3:7-21"},{"book":"Romans","verse":"10:9-13"}]}]},"four":{"title":"FOURTH DAY: Read Romans 5:18-19.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"5:18-19"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_9_8","questionText":"8. What are some results of condemnation, and what impact do these verses have on you? (See Matthew 13:47-50;  Romans 2:8-9; Philippians 3:18-19; 2 Thessalonians 1:8-9; Revelation 20:14-15.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Matthew","verse":"13:47-50"},{"book":"Romans","verse":"2:8-9"},{"book":"Philippians","verse":"3:18-19"},{"book":"2 Thessalonians","verse":"1:8-9"},{"book":"Revelation","verse":"20:14-15"}]},{"id":"2017_9_9a","questionText":"9. a. What is the “one righteous act” that resulted in justification and life? (Use other verses if you wish.)","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_9_9b","questionText":"9. b. What are some results of life in Christ, and how are they evident in your life? (See John 10:28; Galatians 2:20; Ephesians 3:12; Philippians 3:20-21; Hebrews 13:20-21.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"John","verse":"10:28"},{"book":"Galatians","verse":"2:20"},{"book":"Ephesians","verse":"3:12"},{"book":"Philippians","verse":"3:20-21"},{"book":"Hebrews","verse":"13:20-21"}]}]},"five":{"title":"FIFTH DAY: Read Romans 5:20-21.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"5:20-21"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_9_10a","questionText":"10. a. Why does law cause trespass (sin) to increase? (See Romans 7:7-12; Galatians 3:24.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"7:7-12"},{"book":"Galatians","verse":"3:24"}]},{"id":"2017_9_10b","questionText":"10. b. How do you see this principle at work in you, your family, community or country?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_9_11","questionText":"11. Share briefly a recent example of God’s grace overcoming the consequences of your sin.","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_9_12","questionText":"12. What are the two reigns (kingdoms) in verse 21, and what happens to those who belong to each kingdom? (See also Colossians 1:13-14.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Colossians","verse":"1:13-14"}]}]},"six":{"title":"SIXTH DAY: Review Romans 5:12-21.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"5:12-21"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_9_13","questionText":"13. What have you learned about God in this week’s study? How may your group pray for you as you make this truth a part of your life?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_9_14","questionText":"14. Homiletics for group and administrative leaders: Romans 5:12-21","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"5:12-21"}]}]}}}